
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Statues challenge Brussels</string>
    <string name="title_activity_maps"></string>
    <string name="Welcome">Statues challenge Brussels</string>
    <string name="start">Start the challange</string>
    <string name="ask_permision">Location is required.</string>
    <string name="permission_ok">allow</string>
    <string name="title_activity_question">Questions</string>
    <string name="snackbarCameraPermission">Camera is required to scan QR codes.</string>
    <string name="standbeeldenStart">Statues</string>
    <string name="info">Information about the statue</string>
    <string name="location">Nearby</string>
    <string name="nameMannekepis">Manneke pis</string>
    <string name="jeanekepis">Jeaneke pis</string>
    <string name="leopold">Horseman statue Leopold II</string>
    <string name="godfried">Godfried van Bouillon</string>
    <string name="continue_the_tour">Continue the challange</string>
    <string name="descriptionMannekepis">The 58 cm big boy on a pedestal is placed at the corner of the Stoofstraat and the Eikstraat, not far from the Grote Markt.

It has become one of the most famous Belgian and Brussels monuments and a symbol / mascot of the city of Brussels.

Besides the Manneken Pis of Brussels, there is also one in Geraardsbergen, Westmeerbeek, Broksele and Koksijde, but Brussels is the best known.

From 1452 the name Manneken Pis appears in the archives.

The original of the current bronze statuette was made by Hieronymus Duquesnoy the Elder in 1619 on behalf of the city council as the decoration of a public fountain. It seems as if the boy is urinating. On special occasions, he pees beer or wine instead of water.

Around 1745, English soldiers kidnapped him in secret, but the people of Brussels brought in the thieves in Geraardsbergen thanks to the helpful citizens of that city. As a token of their appreciation, Brussels people gave this city a replica of the figurine.</string>

    <string name="descriptionJeanekepis">Jeanneke Pis is a statue in the center of Brussels of a girl who is urinating.

The figurine was placed in 1987 on the initiative of the local merchants with the intention of attracting more visitors to their street.

The image is placed in the back of the dead-end Getrouwheidsgang.

The statue is just between the house numbers 10 and 12.</string>

    <string name="descriptionLeopold">
This equestrian statue of King Leopold II was inaugurated on November 15, 1926, about the same place where Leopold II himself ever took his oath. Leopold II was king of Belgium from 1865 until his death in 1909. This bronze statue was made by sculptor Thomas Vinçotte and architect François Malfait.

Inscription at the end of the sculpture: "The copper and tin of this statue come from the Belgian Congo"
    </string>
    <string name="descriptionGodfried">
Godfrey of Bouillon was Duke of Lower Lorraine (from 1089-1100) and one of the leaders of the First Crusade. He was also proclaimed the first king of the kingdom of Jerusalem but refused that title.

After the independence of Belgium in 1830, the young government decided to place statues of great figures from the "national" past throughout the country. The equestrian statue of Godfrey of Bouillon, created by Eugène Simonis in 1848, has since been central to Koningsplein.
    </string>
    <string name="hoegrootismannekepisAntw1">58 cm</string>
    <string name="hoegrootismannekepisAntw2">1m 20cm</string>
    <string name="hoegrootismannekepisAntw3">1m</string>
    <string name="hoegrootismannenpisVraag">How big is Manneken Pis?</string>
    <string name="geraardsbergen">Geraardsbergen</string>
    <string name="halle">Halle</string>
    <string name="aalst">Aalst</string>
    <string name="WaarstaaternogeenmannekenpisVraag">In what other belgian city stands Manneken Pis?</string>
    <string name="data1987">1987</string>
    <string name="data1948">1948</string>
    <string name="data2002">2002</string>
    <string name="InwelkjaarisjeanekepisgeplaatstVraag">In which year was Jeaneke Pis placed?</string>
    <string name="huisnummer1012">10 - 12</string>
    <string name="huisnummer2527">25 - 27</string>
    <string name="huisnummer12">1 - 2</string>
    <string name="tussenwelkehuisnummersstaatzeVraag">Between which house numbers is she sitting?</string>
    <string name="oostende">Oostende</string>
    <string name="brugge">Brugge</string>
    <string name="antwerpen">Antwerpen</string>
    <string name="InwelkestadstaatnogeenleopoldVraag">In what other belgian city stands a horseman statue of Leopold II?</string>
    <string name="data1848">1848</string>
    <string name="data1100">1100</string>
    <string name="data1830">1830</string>
    <string name="InwelkjaarisgodfriedgemaaktVraag">In what year was the statue of Godfrey of Bouillon sized?</string>
    <string name="next">Next</string>

</resources>
